[theme music playing]
[Emilia] I promise to continue getting rid
of the evil in our town.
They're willing to take anyone
down just to clear their name.
So don't mingle with those devils.
How will I get justice for my family
if I act like a coward?
For my first project,
let me introduce to you
a good friend of mine, Miss Ivy Aguas!
I see that you're still siding
with the Ardientes, Senator.
What's your game, Miss Aguas?
If I tell you,
you might not want
to play anymore, Senator.
Maybe you can promote me in our party
as a replacement candidate for Papa.
I knew it. Your friendship
comes with a price.
If you can't reach Julio's
level of influence,
you'll only be wasting time and money
because you'll surely lose.
Jasmin's gone. I've searched
the whole house for her.
Auntie, didn't I ask you
to keep an eye on her?
Hi, Mr. Torillo. You look tense.
Some of my men are stealing from me.
You better be careful.
-Ivy?
-Your son likes her.
I'm not interested in that woman.
You all need to vacate this property.
I don't think this is right.
What about our livelihood?
You know, this is useless!
We've already issued an eviction notice!
You don't have to side with them on this!
If you'd only hear them out,
you'd understand that
what you're doing is wrong.
[Emilia] You're wasting my time. Leave.
-Mom.
-Leave!
[Raul] Diego!
What do you need? Maybe I can help.
Nothing, Dad.
I'm sorry, but you can't help me.
You're leaving anyway, right?
I'm leaving, all right.
I really want to go,
but I want you to know
that the only reason
I keep coming back here is because of you.
Never forget that I'm on your side.
I hope so, Dad.
-It's really slippery here.
-So then, all is set.
Mr. Fernan, Mr. Ramon, I trust
you can unite the farmers.
Tell them to cooperate
to avoid any trouble.
-Yes, Mayor.
Hey, Diego!
What are you doing here, Arnaldo?
We just settled some things for the EPZ.
The mayor already gave
the notice of eviction.
It's a month from today.
What?
Arnaldo, you can't do this!
There's no point fighting. It's done.
Everything's finalized. Just accept it.
[Fernan] Careful, Miss Ivy! It's slippery.
It just rained.
[Arnaldo] Ivy, can you manage?
Ivy! Careful!
-Thank you.
-[Fernan] Be careful, Miss Ivy.
-It's slippery.
-Hold on to me.
[romantic music playing]
Oh, thank you.
-Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
-Sure.
Yeah. I'm okay. Let's go?
-Oh!
-Hey! Hey!
-Oh, no!
-Watch out!
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary playing]
-Hold on. Careful.
-Um…
Give me your hand.
-I'm okay.
-You need to change, though.
No, no, I'm okay.
I'll just change at home.
You can change at Auntie Loring's.
No need. Ivy wants to go home now.
It's close by. You can wash there, too.
-No. Thank you, Mr. Torillo.
-Oh, no! Careful!
Come on. It won't take long.
-Hey! Why are you so stubborn?!
-[shrieking]
-Diego!
-It won't take long!
Mr. Torillo, put me down!
-You need to clean yourself up.
-What is your brother doing?
[Diego] I'm only helping you,
so stop complaining.
Thank you so much for the goodies.
Yeah. Thank you, friend. Thank you.
[soft tense music playing]
Aww.
The thing is, those aren't my favorites.
Wildflowers?
It's so barbaric, untamed, uncivilized.
[Emilia sighs]
Come on, Emilia.
Let me ask you. Since you got
rid of Dante Cruz's family…
do you remember any instances
or heard any rumors
that I've womanized again?
You haven't, right?
So, please, don't be so cold.
Especially now that
our anniversary's coming up.
Wow, you actually remembered.
That's a miracle.
Nanny!
Can I have a vase for these flowers?
But before anything else,
I need to go to San Ildefonso.
They have game fowl over there.
I'm thinking of buying some
since they'll do well for business.
San Ildefonso? That far?
I'll be back right away.
In time for our anniversary.
Emilia, I'll make sure we'll get
to celebrate our anniversary.
Nanny! Where's the vase I asked for?
[Emilia sighs]
[Emilia humming]
Miss Ivy, you can get dressed here.
I'm sorry. It's a bit cramped.
It's fine.
I hope you're okay with
these clothes we borrowed.
They're great, thanks.
Miss Loring?
I'm sorry we had to be
the bearer of bad news earlier.
But thank you because you still
welcomed us and helped me out.
It's okay.
I also apologize for coming off
a bit rude earlier.
It's fine.
Believe it or not…
I do understand.
Please, go ahead and change.
I'll leave you to it.
All right.
I didn't like what you did earlier.
Did I do something wrong?
I even helped her out.
What a priss.
You know what I mean.
What's mine is mine.
What's yours is yours.
And Natalie?
Isn't she your girlfriend?
Arnaldo, if you always got
what you wanted back then,
it won't happen this time.
What do you mean?
Ivy doesn't like you.
She's just using you. Both you and Mom.
And that's the reason
why I will never like her.
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary playing]
-[screams]
-Oh!
-Miss Aguas, I'm sorry!
-My god!
Mr. Torillo, what were you doing?
-Why were you peeping on me?
-I'm sorry! I didn't mean it!
You didn't mean it?!
Miss Aguas, I didn't know. I'm sorry.
-How dare you peep on me!
-I'm sorry! Come on!
-Sorry?!
-Sorry. Ow! That hurts!
-I don't accept it!
-It hurts!
-Why did you peep on me?!
-I wasn't peeping!
You did! What else can you call that?
I didn't peep on you.
I was going to my room.
-Okay, fine! Sorry!
-Ouch! Hey!
So your eyes just unconsciously
ran over my body, is that it?
[laughing] Hey, Butchoy!
That looks good.
Looks like you ate all my cooking, too.
Should I make some more?
It's really good, Miss Loring!
Your banana fritters are
the best! They're perfect!
[laughs]
Oh, you flatter me!
I'll get you some water to wash it down.
I'll do it, Miss Loring!
You're just trying to get more
food, aren't you? [chuckles]
Mayor, are you okay?
[Loring chuckles softly]
-Well?!
-I didn't mean it!
So you admit that you peeped on me!
Ouch, it hurts!
How should I know you were in there?!
-You peeped on me!
-That hurts! Hey!
Diego. Miss Beautiful.
What are you two doing?
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary playing]
-Uh, miss–
-Miss Loring, we have a winner!
A winner? What winner?
Um, Miss Loring, thanks again.
I have to go.
Miss Aguas.
It's okay, I'll get it.
I'm sorry about what happened.
Let's go.
Mayor, Miss Ivy.
Why don't you eat with us
before you leave?
-That's right, Mayor.
-Yeah.
I agree.
It's a tradition here to hold
a feast after every harvest.
Uh, I don't think it's necessary,
but thank you for the time.
We'll be going now.
Miss Beautiful.
When are you coming back?
Not anytime soon, Butchoy. Why?
So we won't see each other
for a while then?
Something like that.
Then stay and eat with us.
Please, Miss Beautiful.
I'm going to miss you.
[crowd chuckling]
-[Fernan] Stay for a while.
-It's up to you.
Okay, Butchoy.
Yay! Miss Beautiful is staying! Yay!
[chuckling]
[Loring] There you go.
Miss Beautiful's staying.
[Butchoy] Yay!
[Emilia] Raul.
Our charity event is in two weeks' time.
You have to be back by then.
And people should see us
together more often in public.
I know. Besides, we'll go out next week.
And I told you, I'll be back
for our anniversary.
If you say so.
[ominous music playing]
[line rings]
Hello, Mayor Mendoza?
Yes.
Raul is on his way to Ildefonso.
I won't be there with him.
Besides, he'll be there for business.
Can you make sure you receive him well?
Thanks.
[ominous music playing]
-Look at all the food!
-There we go!
Nanny, add some more tomatoes here.
-Mayor!
-There's so much food.
Miss Ivy!
Sit here. Come on!
-Come here!
-Let's sit here.
-Sit with us.
-Take your seats.
Miss Beautiful, sit beside me.
[chuckles] All right. I'll sit beside you.
All right, then. Let's settle down.
We don't have any utensils.
Where can I wash my hands?
[chuckling]
Mayor, it's a boodle fight.
We just gobble up.
But if you have to, you can wash here.
We also have one over there.
-Let's wash our hands first.
-That's right.
-Let's wash first.
-Here.
[romantic music playing]
-Mayor, for Miss Ivy.
-Let's go over there. Come on.
-Miss Aguas.
[romantic music continues playing]
Give me that.
Here, Miss Beautiful.
Thank you, Butchoy.
[Loring] All right, sirs….
[Ivy] You go wash, too.
[Loring] All right. Before we start.
Here, Fernan.
Okay?
Nanny, where's Uncle Pandoy?
Oh! He'll catch up later.
He has something to take care of.
Get some food. Don't be shy.
-Diego?
-All right.
Do you want me to get you some shrimp?
I'm fine, Nimfa. Thank you.
Sure.
Here, Butchoy.
Hey, why don't you have more food?
I'm trying to lose weight,
so my playmates will stop bullying me.
Your playmates bully you?
Here, have some more.
You know, you shouldn't
let them bully you.
They might get used to it.
But how do I fight them? Do I sit on them?
[chuckling]
-Butchoy.
-Oh, that boy.
If only you could.
But of course, you can't do that.
You should tell them that
what they're doing is wrong.
On your end, try to be more active.
You know what?
When Miss Beautiful has time…
I'll exercise with you.
[Butchoy] You will?
I can't wait!
-Okay, Miss Beautiful!
-[chuckles]
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary playing]
I'll help you not gain weight
even if you eat a lot!
Go, Diego! Keep running!
I knew you could do it!
It was hard, but you did it!
All right. Now, eat up.
[Loring] He's like Diego
when he was younger.
He used to eat everything!
Banana fritters,
and especially a huge roast.
[laughing]
-Nanny, don't embarrass me.
-But it's true!
But look at him now. I'm proud of him.
Just look at his body!
That's because his best friend
taught him how to exercise.
Who's his best friend?
[scoffs] Obviously, me.
After all, I'm Diego's
only best friend here.
We grew up in Ardiente together.
We both studied in Manila
and returned to Ardiente together.
[Loring chuckles]
You've been best friends
since you were kids, Nimfa?
Uh…
The truth is, Miss Ivy…
We only became friends during high school.
[Loring laughs] That's true.
When Diego was a kid,
he had only one best friend,
and she was his one and only true love.
[teasing]
Here we go!
There you go again, Nanny.
Why are you blushing?
-[laughing]
-Seriously, Diego?
That was so long ago.
You still think about her?
What's her name, Diego?
Uh…
Lily.
Her name is Lily.
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary playing]
[Butchoy] Where's Lily now?
Uh…
Well, Lily left years ago.
They never came back to Ardiente.
I wonder where she is now.
Let's stop talking about her, Miss Loring.
I think the mayor and Miss Ivy
are getting bored
listening to Diego talk about
his long-lost best friend.
[Loring] Oh, I'm sorry.
Besides, it's all in the past.
It should just stay there.
Right?
[Loring] Don't be shy. Eat some more.
Um… Let me get that for you.
I want you to keep eating.
I don't want you to get hungry.
There. You can eat it.
Thank you, Miss Beautiful!
Yummy!
[chuckling]
You're so cute!
[young Lily] You like it, huh?
You're so cute! [chuckles]
[chuckling]
[romantic music playing]
Uh, ma'am, should I still serve
the meat roll?
Are you sure you can
finish all that by yourself?
Don't take the meat roll out.
Take yourself out of this room instead!
And don't come in until I say so.
Sorry, ma'am.
[tense music playing]
Where is she?
Jasmin, I was so worried
about you, so I rushed here.
I'm sorry.
I will stay with you until you get better.
Uh, we should get going.
Thank you so much for dinner.
And Miss Loring, like what I said earlier,
I'm really thankful.
Even though we have our differences,
you still welcomed us. Me and the mayor.
[Fernan] That's how the people
of Ardiente are, Miss Ivy.
We're always ready to lend a helping hand.
All I want to say is we should
just trust our leaders.
We won't do anything
that would harm the town.
But the farmers have a right to be heard.
I'll leave a request
for dialogue at your office,
so you and Mom can listen to their side.
Make sure you won't waste our time.
What do you think, Ivy?
Um… Mr. Mayor,
this will delay our project.
[tense music playing]
But maybe holding
a dialogue wouldn't hurt.
I'll talk to the governor.
I'll talk to your mother, Mr. Torillo.
Thank you, Miss Aguas.
All right. Thank you.
[Fernan] Thank you, Mayor.
[Loring] Thank you.
[Raul] This will get better
soon. We just have to treat it.
Don't worry.
As long as I'm here, you'll be okay.
Hello, Mayor Mendoza.
Have you met up with Raul?
Oh, yes. He mentioned he needs
to do something first before meeting you.
Maybe that's why he's not there.
All right. Thanks, Mayor.
I'll update you once I get hold of Raul.
Thank you.
[Emilia] A dialogue with those farmers?
Why would I do that, Ivy?
Besides, they'll be evicted soon.
This is a necessary step, Emilia.
In my business,
this is how we check the
intricacies of land ownership.
Sometimes, this is how we discover
whether or not the property is viable.
I hope those farmers
don't test my patience, Ivy.
If this problem doesn't end…
I'll end them myself.
[dramatic music playing]
1958?
[unsettling music playing]
[unsettling music continues playing]
I knew it.
Arnaldo, what is this?
Why does this document state
that the Ardientes don't own
the lot that you want?
[tense music playing]
Uncle Pandoy was right.
Our ancestors gave the lot to the farmers.
Who hid this? You?
-[scoffs]
-Or Grandpa?
First of all…
Don't go through my things.
Second, don't drag Grandpa
into your nonsense.
-The farmers have a chance.
-Shut it.
What will you do with this?
Will you use it against your family?
See?
You can't do it.
[gasps]
[dramatic music playing]
[Arnaldo] So let me get this straight.
You made a promise to Diego?
Don't worry about upsetting him.
He's as harmless as a fish.
It's about Emilia.
Is she going through something?
I just don't understand why she can't see
that when explaining
these things to the farmers,
we have to be patient.
Well, that land rightfully
belongs to the Ardientes.
And those farmers?
Just push them out!
Force them out and put up
a fence so they can't trespass.
Well, it's not that easy, Natalie.
There is a process.
Oh, come on.
We all know you're just
prolonging the process
so you can spend more time
with my boyfriend. Am I right?
I have no time for this.
Don't you dare stand
while I'm still talking to you!
Arnaldo, can you please
not bring your girlfriend
to our next business meeting?
You're a snake!
A tease and cheap counterfeit--
Don't try me, Natalie.
[screams]
[suspenseful music playing]
Miss Aguas.
Mr. Torillo.
Good luck.
Mr. Mayor.
Shall we?
Governor. Madam…
The dialogue is about to start.
Do you even think I have
the slightest interest
for such nonsense?
Let's go back to the mansion.
Gov! Governor Emilia!
Gov.
We just want to let you know
that we have full confidence
in your plans for our town.
Is that so, Fernan? Thank you.
Hello, Ramon.
What are you waiting for? Let's go in.
Let's go in, friends!
-Thank you!
-Thank you, Governor!
We do understand
that you've been staying
on that land for a long time.
That's why we will make sure
to relocate all of you.
[Emilia] We'll also provide you
with sufficient funds
so you can start over.
WERE YOU ABLE TO FIND A WAY
TO GIVE THE DOCUMENT TO DIEGO?
[Emilia] We only want the best for you.
We want you all to have better lives
because we truly care about you.
[crowd murmuring]
I PUT THE DOCUMENT
AMONG DIEGO'S THINGS.
[crowd murmuring]
Mom.
Madam Governor.
It's stated here that our ancestors
gave that land to the farmers.
[Emilia] Come on, Diego.
That's just an old wives' tale.
Only fools would believe in those rumors.
But there is truth in every story.
I only had to find out
that one piece of information
to unearth what's been
kept secret from this town.
Everyone.
I have here an old draft,
the deed of donation from 1958,
confirming that the land
was donated to the farmers.
[crowd murmuring, cheering]
Friends, everyone.
Diego, my son.
Where and how did you get this?
It wasn't even notarized.
Diego, I know you have a heart
for the less fortunate.
But do you really have to get
their hopes up for nothing?
But isn't it worse
to claim a property
that's rightfully theirs?
To abuse their rights because
they've remained silent?
Mom. Everything has its limits.
Now, they've been given a voice.
And they will fight!
-We're going to fight!
-[crowd talking indistinctly]
Please wait.
Silence!
[Fernan] Settle down.
Friends.
I am your governor.
I'd never put any of you in harm's way.
Don't worry.
I will review this document
due to this new development.
-[clapping]
-Thank you, Ma'am Emilia!
You truly took after Señor Julio!
Thank you so much!
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
[dramatic music playing]
[Fernan] Let's just wait for the result.
We will wait.
We still don't know
if the documents are valid.
[indistinct chatter]
[Fernan] Let's hear out the Ardientes.
Let's wait for the result.
Let's trust them.
[indistinct chatter]
Hey, Fernan. Ramon.
Now, do you believe
that the land was donated to us
by the Ardientes' ancestors?
Good thing Diego has an ace up his sleeve.
[giggles] Thank you, Diego, my love.
-"My love"? What are you saying?
-[laughing]
We should also thank
Gov. Emilia and Mayor Arnaldo
for hearing us out.
I was really surprised with Miss Ivy.
She felt for us.
She could've stayed silent
since she's an investor in EPZ,
but she let us have a peaceful dialogue.
Right, Diego?
All right, Nanny. I'll talk to Ms. Aguas.
Diego, thanks again.
I hope your family finally realizes
that they shouldn't belittle
Diego Ardiente-Torillo.
[laughing and cheering]
-Thank you.
-All right, everyone.
Bye!
Madrigal, you may go.
So, you got what you wanted.
When do I get my end of the bargain?
Mr. Mayor…
I'm one of the richest
women in the country.
It's a shame if I only end up
as a small town mayor's other woman.
Touché, but…
who says you're the other woman?
You, Miss Aguas, are the only one.
You're different.
You're ruthless.
Knows what she wants and gets it.
But strangely…
has a heart for the poor.
I can't say for sure,
but it's like the perfect
characteristics of a first lady.
My first lady.
You're the only woman who's
ever made me feel this way.
And I'm sorry if I come
on strong, it's just that
when I'm with you,
I forget about everything else.
Mr. Mayor.
I know that…
you're only acting this way
because that leech you
call a girlfriend isn't here.
Am I right?
Then I think we should
make the most out of it.
[Diego] Miss Aguas, wait!
Miss Aguas!
Mr. Torillo.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to intrude.
Are you referring to what you did earlier?
[tense music playing]
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
How dare you go against your own family?
I'm not going against my family.
I'm just letting you know about
the concerns of the farmers.
You spend every day with them
and fight for their rights.
Whether you admit it or not,
your actions and beliefs
go against the Ardientes, your own family!
Why can't you understand that?
Mr. Mayor.
What? Are you taking his side?
No.
But you shouldn't be fighting here.
I don't care.
If you pull this stunt again…
you will answer to me.
You will answer to me!
Don't forget that.
Mayor, is there a problem?
[tense music playing]
[soft dramatic music playing]
[knocking on door]
Raul?
Hi, good evening, Madam Gov.
I'm just bringing in the laundry.
You again? If you're not
taking something out,
you're bringing something in.
What if I put your head
inside the comforter?!
-Get out!
-I knocked on the door, madam.
Stop talking! Get out of here!
See.
I told you it'd heal right away.
I'll just clean it.
You know what?
Whenever I'm with Emilia…
I feel like a slave who has to
satisfy their every whim.
Not to mention, my father
was Julio's bodyguard.
That's why they look down on me.
They never made me feel accepted
as part of their family.
But I know that someday,
I'll be as powerful as them.
When that happens…
I'll leave Emilia.
And I'll choose you, Camia.
All right, it's late.
You should get some rest.
Babe?
Babe, what's up with you?
[sensual music playing]
You like it rough, huh?
If only I could tell him everything…
so he wouldn't think…
that I'm like the rest of his family.
But I can't.
I can't risk it.
It sounds like…
Diego's opinion matters
a lot to you, dear.
Hey, Diego.
Did you go to Miss Ivy?
Were you able to thank her?
Why should we thank her?
-Huh?
-She's the reason for all this.
-I tried to thank her, Nanny.
-And?
But I couldn't…
because she was with my brother.
Aha! So that's why.
-[Fernan chuckling]
-You got jealous.
It's Diego.
He's my childhood friend.
We've been through a lot together.
But the thing is…
he doesn't know it's me.
Maybe…
you have feelings for him.
[Fernan] Hold on.
The mayor has a girlfriend, right?
Then why is he always with Miss Ivy?
You know, Diego…
If you weren't so angry with Miss Ivy,
I'd say you'd look good together.
It would only ruin my plans.
My dear…
I know you're angry.
But it doesn't mean you're heartless.
Diego is a good man.
You're fighting for the same thing.
It's not wrong to open
your heart to someone, dear.
Hey, hey, hey! Cut it out!
He still has his Lily.
-And Nimfa, too.
-[Loring] Whoa!
[Fernan] Hey! You're too young for that.
Fine, I'll thank her. But that's it.
Because I will never fall for that woman.
Is that so? Are you sure?
-Look, your nose is growing!
-[laughing]
At least try acting the part.
You're right.
Diego is a good man.
That's why…
I shouldn't drag him into my plans.
-Why didn't you tell me?
-You okay?
-You're playing and seek!
-You said it.
-With your feelings!
-True!
[laughing]
-Cut it out!
-Look!
-Your nose is growing longer.
-See? It's so long now.
[Raul] I need to go to San Ildefonso.
I'll be back in time for our anniversary.
[Emilia] Mayor Mendoza.
Have you met up with Raul?
Oh, yes. He mentioned that
he needs to do something first
before meeting you.
Maybe that's why he's not there.
[Raul] Come on, Emilia.
Since the time you got rid
of Dante Cruz's family,
do you remember any rumors
that I've womanized again?
You haven't, right?
Happy anniversary, my love.
[sobbing]
Happy anniversary? What's so happy? Happy?
What's so happy?!
I'm not happy!
I'm not happy.
[sobbing]
[ominous music playing]
Maid.
Ma'am, do you need anything?
Clean this up.
I don't want to see a speck of dirt here
when I wake up tomorrow.
Yes, ma'am.
[ominous music playing]
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary playing]
Lily.
Thanks for helping me out.
No worries! I got you.
[Loring] I'm so proud of him.
Look at his body.
His best friend taught him
how to exercise.
And she was his one and only true love.
What's her name, Diego?
Lily.
Her name is Lily.
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary
continues playing]
Let me get that for you.
You're so cute!
[Ivy] It's Diego.
-Don't jump! Hey!
-[Ivy] He's my childhood friend.
Oh!
[Ivy] We've been through a lot together.
[Carlotta] Maybe you have
feelings for him.
Diego's a good man.
It's not wrong to open
your heart to someone.
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary
continues playing]
[Ivy] What is this feeling?
I'm confused.
Am I holding on to the memories
of when we were still friends?
[Fernan] You know, Diego?
If you weren't so angry with Miss Ivy,
you'd look good together.
-[screams]
-Oh!
[Diego] I will never fall for that woman.
[Loring] You're playing hide
and seek with your feelings!
-[Fernan] True!
-[laughter]
I shouldn't feel this way about
you because you're the enemy.
But… why can't I get you off my mind?
I heard your son, Diego,
tried to stop the project.
Sorry to say, but
if you can't control your son,
what more the people of Ardiente?
I can't help but think
that if Grandpa were here,
-we wouldn't be having problems.
-I'm the one here.
And I'm more than capable
of solving these problems.
-Wait!
-Miss Aguas! Miss Aguas!
Mr. Mayor, make them stop.
There's a child here!
-Have some mercy!
-[screaming]
[Diego] You don't have a court
order because we all know
this didn't go through the due process!
The farmers will file an appeal!
[Emilia] It's good that happened,
so they get the message
that they shouldn't be going
against the Ardientes.
[theme music playing]